<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chu's Digital Log - posts</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://chunnodu.com/feeds/posts.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://chunnodu.com/</id><updated>2025-11-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Perspective</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/perspective.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2025-11-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-11-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2025-11-10:/blog/perspective.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A random thing that still fascinates me is how you can experience the same weather …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A random thing that still fascinates me is how you can experience the same weather very differently, depending on your current activity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When running in below 5 degrees celsius weather, it feels so cold starting out vs after a few miles when I’m warmed up and coasting by pedestrians shivering as they walk.
The weather hasn’t really changed, our recent activity  has just conditioned us to experience it differently at that time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same happens with our lived history and how it affects our reaction to circumstances.
I think I’m starting to view life’s events more dispassionately as I get older. A lot of things that happen aren’t objectively bad or good, until our reaction to them seals the deal one way or the other. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Okechukwu_Enelamah"&gt;Okey Enelamah&lt;/a&gt; speak at HBS ABC in 2014, and one thing that stayed with me from his talk was a proverb about recognizing the advantage of your position, whether big or small. A mouse has to find and take the advantage that the elephant can’t.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="chunitycard"/></entry><entry><title>Just like MacGyver</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/just-like-macgyver.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2025-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2025-10-28:/blog/just-like-macgyver.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like scented candles, so it always annoyed me when some of the ones I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I like scented candles, so it always annoyed me when some of the ones I bought would burn in a funny way and leave a lot of wax after the wicks were done. I knew you could melt the candles and buy new wicks, so I didn’t throw them away, but also hadn’t bothered to take any further action. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until last month, when it occurred to me while looking at the melting candle on at my desk, that the wood stick of the Costco ice cream bar I just finished could make a perfect wick replacement. Even better, burning this wick produced the oddly pleasant crackling sound of burning wood, enhancing typically cheaper candles that didn’t come with that type of wick.git&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I melted those leftover candles, and it turned out I had enough wax for a small, medium and large size. I repurposed an ice-cream stick-wick, cutting it into equal pieces, and have started reaping the rewards of my labor from this evening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talking about it with a friend, I vaguely remembered similar things in the past, enough that one time someone described it as “just like MacGyver”, even though I can’t recollect the exact event or person.
I still haven’t seen even a minute of the series till this day, but I was curious then and looked it up, so that was how MacGyver came into my consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These ‘solutions’ I come up with from time to time are hardly rocket science, but it’s always refreshing to put unlikely things together and make them work well for the task at hand. I hope I never lose this creative instinct.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="chunitycard"/></entry><entry><title>The Thrill of Shipping</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/the-thrill-of-shipping.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-01-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-01-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2024-01-23:/blog/the-thrill-of-shipping.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a feeling when you take an idea and execute on it to produce …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s a feeling when you take an idea and execute on it to produce something tangible. It’s such a powerful feeling, and even better in a group setting when you can tangibly feel the excitement of being part of something that actually gets done. This feeling compounds: the more you ship and have finished ‘products’ to look back at, the more motivation to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I’m missing this year is the thrill of shipping in the most basic way: publishing. By just writing a post and publishing it on my blog, I have a finished product that I took from Idea to Action. I hacked it together, so after losing my computer I haven’t quite been able to replicate that setup that allows me post and push to my website. This post started out as nothing but a friendly reminder to myself to fix it so I can feel the thrill of shipping again, but then I remembered that I also have another blog, where my intention was to do more technical, product and career focused writing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This means that there’s no real excuses for not feeling the thrill again, even while my personal blog is down.  I’ve been gathering material slowly, and wasn’t the whole point of this writing challenge to get better at writing? 40 something odd posts in, I should be able to pull together my first serious post of the year, so that’s my goal for this last full week in January: Publish something for &lt;a href="https://www.ajared.ng"&gt;www.ajaRED.ng&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Buying Land in the 2020's</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/buying-land-in-the-2020s.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-12-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-12-07:/blog/buying-land-in-the-2020s.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;African millennials understand the concept of real estate as a source of wealth, but with …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;African millennials understand the concept of real estate as a source of wealth, but with the explosion of the digital landscape, how many have made the connection that digital real estate could work in the same way?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's start from real estate as we know it - buying undervalued land or property and selling it at a profit, usually after the surrounding area becomes more developed. 
We all might have relatives, or know of someone who had the foresight or luck to make such investments in land, it was the way of the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For young people thinking of investing today the question is usually how to go about it. Should we do what our parents' generation did and save money to buy land? My answer is yes, if you can. The truth is land's priced out of reach for most millennial crossing over from their 20's into 30's, when thoughts of investment start coming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how about investing in a website or some other digital property?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you think about it, you probably have the same general concerns while purchasing physical land or digital property from location: where to host your site to how you'll use it: private or commercial, safety of asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a closer look, even the steps for buying land through to use are very similar &lt;em&gt;for digital assets&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;pay for land | &lt;em&gt;buying a domain name&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;necessary registration | &lt;em&gt;buying hosting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;secure land by fencing | &lt;em&gt;setting up landing page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;start building, start use | emails like yourname@yourdomain once registered **&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;complete building  | &lt;em&gt;start full personal/commercial use&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;maintenance | maintenance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;**&lt;em&gt;Like physical land, you can start using even while still building. These emails make you look professional, even without a website - I did this for years with great results while figuring out what to use the site for.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What if the 2021 version of buying land like your parents did was buying a digital asset, or some "space on the internet"?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's some ideas for how you could use it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like shops on physical land, online stores can be 'built' to sell physical or digital products. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A site where people come to use your facilities/services, and pay you for the time spent, just like a hotel!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal blog: your ideas, like the one you're reading have a home, and you can invite people there to visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, with digital you aren't stuck to any choices &amp;amp; can change or combine uses more easily. Now, go buy some 'land' so you can reap the benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>To be Remembered, Teach People things!</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/to-be-remembered-teach-people-things.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-12-01:/blog/to-be-remembered-teach-people-things.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This refreshing video of Adele's reunion with her old teacher spawned a lot of great …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This refreshing video of Adele's reunion with her old teacher spawned a lot of great comments about teachers &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/search?q=never%20forget%20a%20good%20teacher&amp;amp;src=typed_query"&gt;on twitter&lt;/a&gt;, where I hang out a lot in my free time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;We all have that one teacher who changed our life… such a beautiful reunion! ❤️&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;*PS, would totally buy Alan Carr’s version of ‘Make You Feel My Love* 🤣&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Adele?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;@Adele&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/AnAudienceWithAdele?src=hash&amp;amp;ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;#AnAudienceWithAdele&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/2ZZI2RS0mI"&gt;https://t.co/2ZZI2RS0mI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/hlTOOZKt5j"&gt;pic.twitter.com/hlTOOZKt5j&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; ITV (@ITV) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/ITV/status/1462518771864805377?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw"&gt;November 21, 2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You never forget a good teacher", was the common sentiment, as some people shared anecdotes about their favorite teachers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bringing it home, one thing that set apart the teachers I really enjoyed was their attitude and enthusiasm. I'd say their mastery of the subject too, but i suspect that was a natural result of being so interested in and engaged with anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even going beyond teachers - from the girl in my university class who taught me how to win the Minesweeper game and not get blown up (thanks Sylvia!) to my boss after college who showed me how to mind-map(because mind-mapping changed my life) - I think you truly remember anyone who taught you something useful, profound, difficult or remarkable in some other way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad certainly didn't forget the older man at his office who put him on to investing in stocks back in the day, because when I asked about it almost 30 years later, the answer came in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can stop the examples now. The point is we never forget good teachers, so to be remembered - teach people things!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>The Spark: Theory, Practice, and why I’m betting on Africa.</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/the-spark-theory-practice-and-why-im-betting-on-africa.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-11-30:/blog/the-spark-theory-practice-and-why-im-betting-on-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took piano lessons as a teenager from when i was around 12-14. Mr. Johnson …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I took piano lessons as a teenager from when i was around 12-14. Mr. Johnson was a good teacher, we used Smallwood's piano tutorial and by the time i gave it up i was able to play pieces in C, G and F. Now? I can only play basic nursery rhymes from memory, but at least I have an ear for music, or a brain that thinks so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand some kids I grew up with learned how to play the piano at church. They probably still picked up reading music along the way, but if i remember correctly they learned chords first, then how to freestyle and improv to accompany the choir's songs until they got really good, picked up multiple instruments and could soon play in the grown-up choir. I bet they can still play today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had the spark, I had some theory and even back then when I couldn't articulate it, I could tell there was a difference. With the benefit of experience i understand now that &lt;a href="https://plato.stanford.edu/entries/episteme-techne/"&gt;both&lt;/a&gt; techne - &lt;em&gt;know how&lt;/em&gt;, and episteme - &lt;em&gt;know what/why&lt;/em&gt; are necessary for really brilliant work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I talk about childhood with native-born Americans, the options, tools and resources they had available to develop potential in almost any area are fascinating for someone who grew up outside the western world. Structured programs, mentoring, camps, even having affordable chains of stores dedicated to games, music equipment, arts and craft?  Mind-blowing, and priceless to a 3rd world child. "You should all be prodigy's with that much formative experience, and the world of possibilities it unlocks" is what i keep thinking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday a  friend and I agreed that just as 3rd world kids were heavy on creativity but lacking in the tools and resources to take their craft to the next level, what was usually missing on this end was that spark of curiosity, creativity or the chance of some real world application that made folks persist and actually master the craft until their work got outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift that's happening now in Africa is that with technology like the internet and mobile phones, people with &lt;em&gt;the spark&lt;/em&gt; are either finding the tools and resources to build up their theory and practice, or getting connected to others who already have this down pat and can speed up their growth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bottom line: a continental explosion of both technical talent and creative genius - Afrobeat artistes blowing up is the old story, professional talent is on the come up too with the producers, designers, business people, writers. Even getting more technical - African developers and designers are starting to write software and design experiences that the world uses, without having left the continent. 
We've had the spark, but now with the theory and tools  - and practice in the coming years, you'll see just how that can make things different.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>15 things to do if you lose your job</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/15-things-to-do-if-you-lose-your-job.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-11-03:/blog/15-things-to-do-if-you-lose-your-job.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Losing your job or regular source of income is a probability at some point for …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Losing your job or regular source of income is a probability at some point for most working people. Not sure what the stats are, but daresay that anyone who goes through life without any periods of unemployment must be in the lucky minority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without diving into specifics, think about the related loss of motivation, position, influence, identity, confidence that could come with it. Pretty major life change, huh? So, it's interesting that most people don't have a plan for this dreaded event that &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working in the US as an expat with very interesting hiring and immigration restrictions, this wasn't my first rodeo - so when I got let go at the start of the pandemic, I knew better from previous times and approached it as a storm that I had to survive. Here are some things that helped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Before the storm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preparing starts before the event, so save 3months/6months/1year of your salary or living expenses.
&lt;em&gt;It could take 1-3 months+ to get and start a new job. This keeps you from instant anxiety, and allows you to execute any short term plans without any immediate disruptive changes to your standard of living. I had over a year's saved so I was good, but didn't think i'd actually have to burn through most of it, which ended up happening.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on a 1-3 month improvement plan: pick one thing from your list of "with more time i'd love to learn/do X" and get started.
&lt;em&gt;It doesn't have to be specifically career focused, could be a life goal but as the 'chief athlete' of your 'professional team', you have to stay in the game and be sure not to get rusty&lt;/em&gt;. 
    &lt;!--I got a new product management credential i'd had my eyes on for 7 years since grad school, and also got certified as a python developer._--&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a disaster recovery or "what-to-do-if-i-lose-my-job" plan that you can take action on in your current situation i.e not a wishlist - things you can actually do, with the resources you have.     &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;During the storm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don't know how long it'll last. Assume at least 3 months, and start doing your things for the quarter. 
&lt;em&gt;Could be learning an instrument, a new skill, or hobby - as long as it's something within your control to make progress on, that you find rewarding. Almost counter intuitive to my tip on budgets but take a short holiday to reset if you can, problem no de finish and yours might be just...hmm.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stabilize or reduce your running costs. Get into a monthly routine of expenses so it's clear what it costs you to operate at a baseline level through this time.
    &lt;em&gt;I went down to a third of my 'pre-storm budget' and quickly understood the difference between essentials and nice-to-haves. Essentials kept me sane, others I could do without for some time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise daily, or at least take a 30 min walk everyday to get fresh air and clear your head.
    &lt;em&gt;Now, you have more free time for this. Your mind and body are linked so working out gets your mental engine firing as well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat good: Eat healthy, don't binge eat.
    &lt;em&gt;The link with food &amp;amp; your mood will be very observable now. I like cooking so, used the time to perfect my skills and try new things. Cooking's great for your budget and health too.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engage with your spiritual source through introspection, prayer, meditation, or whatever spiritual practice checks this box for you. 
    &lt;em&gt;You should slow down, get and stay centered for clarity on what your direction or next steps should be.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get socially involved: in anything that brings you into contact with people for a common goal e.g meetup groups, volunteer.
    &lt;em&gt;Working on something with others gives a sense of purpose, even if you're not getting paid. If you're not burnt out it could be good to replicate this feeling until your next paid role.&lt;/em&gt; 
    &lt;!--I joined the Personal Knowledge Graph working group and drank from the firehose on an area i'd been meaning to explore for a while...Linked Data and the Semantic Web, with exciting results so far._--&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find your optimal work/life routine and lean into it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a lot more and attend events you'd normally miss because of timing at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work harder for yourself than you have for any employer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;After the storm&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you land the next role, take a step back, see what you accomplished and beef up those savings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update your disaster recovery or "what if i lose my job plan".&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pay it forward, write/share your lessons during the storm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Enter the Flatmate from Hell</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/enter-the-flatmate-from-hell.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-11-02:/blog/enter-the-flatmate-from-hell.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;They don't replace things they use, and get sullen when called out. They avoid making …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;They don't replace things they use, and get sullen when called out. They avoid making any firm commitments or get mad when asked to, and will agree to things they won't do instead of speaking up to say just that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too big or busy to respond to calls for chores, they stay disconnected from general maintenance routines around the house. Their angry verbal/physical reactions when issues are raised make you dread engaging, and overlook instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who can easily go months late on rent without talking about it, rack up debts without tracking or payback?  You guessed right, &lt;strong&gt;your flatmate from hell&lt;/strong&gt;. Quite needy in times of lack, but surprisingly selfish in times of plenty? Does this ring a bell?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I've known &lt;a href="https://chunnodu.com/posts/2021-11-01-good-flatmate-bad-flatmate.html"&gt;good and bad flatmates&lt;/a&gt;, but once I ran into this other type.  Zero contribution most times, but 100% entitlement to an equal share. 
Prayed in loud voices and spoke in tongues, but went 6 months without speaking to folks who were subsidizing his rent. Funny, when conflicts happened he would still be the first one to yell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did he move out after finding his feet to give his hosts some needed space? Of course not. A classic poor communicator, even basics like "discuss move out plans without prompting" and "leave as stated", got complicated. The dates dragged months, then into and over a year so it was quite in character when his confirmed move out date finally came by to spot him still at the apartment,without a word to anyone saying why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remarkably, these types always approach as the original term runs out to say "Hey, let's move in together again"  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AND GO THROUGH ALL THIS AGAIN? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See, these flatmates are never self-aware enough to understand that anyone who's lived through hell, would never want a part 2.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Good Flatmate, Bad Flatmate</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/good-flatmate-bad-flatmate.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-11-01:/blog/good-flatmate-bad-flatmate.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad flatmates&lt;/strong&gt; take and don't replace until you call them out. They make and break …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bad flatmates&lt;/strong&gt; take and don't replace until you call them out. They make and break commitments, or wait to be called out before doing their part. You'll need to prompt them to take action because a bad flatmate communicates late or infrequently about plans affecting others, and will probably only react after general issues come up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, they could leave you worried about making rent and will probably have to be reminded of debts, but mostly catch up eventually, after stressing you out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad flatmates are typically fairly independent both in times of lack or plenty, and have been known to move out without giving much notice for others to make plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A good flatmate&lt;/strong&gt; uses and replaces things before you notice, but still tells you anyways just so you don't get surprised. They make and stick to commitments, or renegotiate them early when things come up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proactive and open about general concerns, a good flatmate communicates early and often about plans e.g. rent, chores and quickly resolves general issues to maintain harmony. They are open about thoughts and feelings, interactions with flatmates and propose or are open to early conflict resolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of rent - good flatmates are rarely or never late on rent without advance notice.
They keep records and pay back everything they owe - being independent in times of lack, and generous in times of plenty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, when the chapter is over, good flatmates discuss move out plans ahead of time with up to a month's notice, and can commit and stick to a move out schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, meet the &lt;a href="https://chunnodu.com/posts/2021-11-02-enter-the-flatmate-from-hell.html"&gt;"Flatmate from Hell"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Why I want to #Ship30for30</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/why-i-want-to-ship30for30.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-09-21T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-09-21:/blog/why-i-want-to-ship30for30.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Ship30for30, or publish 30 atomic articles in 30 days feels an opportunity for me to …&lt;/h1&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Ship30for30, or publish 30 atomic articles in 30 days feels an opportunity for me to fall into a good writing habit, especially because of my underlying feeling that with all the reading I do, I could be a better writer than I currently am.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From waiting to get a new computer to 'make typing more interesting' to planning to start at the beginning of September because "30 days has september", I have procrastinated in unimaginable ways since hearing about it online for the first time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally sitting down to sign up to the cohort, I found out it wasn't a free internet challenge but a paid writing course...nope. I wasn't that interested. Did I really need another writing course? Maybe i'll just ship 30 anyways? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wait...the official website had a teaser into the Ship 30 for 30 program: a writing lesson emailed to you each day for 10 days. I found these very useful, and have no reasons to procrastinate any further, so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Celebrating Title Blocks</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/celebrating-title-blocks.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-02-23T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-02-23T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-02-23:/blog/celebrating-title-blocks.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I learnt an interesting life lesson from one of the faculty who taught &lt;em&gt;Engineering Drawing …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I learnt an interesting life lesson from one of the faculty who taught &lt;em&gt;Engineering Drawing: Computer Aided Design&lt;/em&gt; in my 2nd year at university. When the classes got too rowdy and a lot of students had lost concentration, he would keep reminding us about the tests and exams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"You guys not listening now will &lt;strong&gt;celebrate title blocks&lt;/strong&gt; during the exam"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the midterms rolled around the lab was deadly quiet
as we all dug into our engineering drawings on AutoCad, some of us for the first time on our own. As the exam went on he'd walk around looking at our screens, and make these sort of comments on our progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"While some people are done with the first drawing, some of you are still &lt;strong&gt;celebrating title blocks!&lt;/strong&gt;"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some context, here's a title block at the bottom right corner of this engineering drawing sheet. We use them to label and record key details about the work, metadata if you would. The convention is probably to start off with it, although I know some folks who would rather get the drawing out of the way first. &lt;img alt="title block" src="../images/titleblock.png"&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either ways, the point was that although a necessary step, title blocks were a detail only valuable with a completed drawing. After the early stages of the exam you should have moved into the actual drawing material - if you completed the title block and never drew anything else, you'd fail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to fall into that trap in real life. If we get caught up in the planning or minor wins we can  forget that the action, when the rubber meets the road is in &lt;strong&gt;more doing&lt;/strong&gt;: getting traction, not just launching an application. Figuring out a sustainable business model - not just receiving funding. 
 The 15 - 20 repetitious customer interviews after the first interesting ones that you need, to actually start seeing patterns during customer discovery. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how about completing a workout plan or skill acquisition program before posting pictures of your gear/you hard at work. I can't guarantee that the dopamine rush is better when you wait till you've finished but here's my drift...stop celebrating title blocks...get on now with the doing.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>Business Man</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/business-man.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-01-25:/blog/business-man.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An African businessman's response to the question: "As a #businessman sir, what do you do?"&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An African #businessman who was being interviewed about his profession, responded this way to the question:  &lt;strong&gt;"As a #businessman sir, what do you do?"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do #business: I #deal on #deals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have a #gooddeal: you get it to me&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I #like it: I #buy your #deal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have #money to #buy my own: I give you my #bill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You #pay: and that's #business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>Industrious</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/industrious.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2020-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-03-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2020-03-13:/blog/industrious.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date Modified: 2021-03-18
Category: Work
Status: Hidden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product Priorities for Next Quarter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposed order …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date Modified: 2021-03-18
Category: Work
Status: Hidden&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product Priorities for Next Quarter&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My proposed order for prioritization is 
1. Automate IT billbacks :(8) &lt;em&gt;ready for delivery with clear definition of done.&lt;/em&gt; 
2. Renewals &amp;amp; Retention :(7)  &lt;em&gt;discovery - opportunity ID&lt;/em&gt;
3. Broker app :(3)  &lt;em&gt;discovery - pains/problem space&lt;/em&gt;
I weighed our upcoming initiatives for the quarter with an eye out for how quickly we could validate any assumptions around customer delight, return on investment(viability) and feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Next Actions: Work on discovery and delivery sprints with&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;engineers to scope out solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finance to understand cost savings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;designer to research breaks in current renewal flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;customers to understand flow: facility manager - billing + ticketing flow
    member&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sales/marketing - insight into acquisition metrics      &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Assumptions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all broker app are tooling issues - not business process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;facilities request are most frequent customer touchpoint&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;internal knowledge of both systems readily available for integration
/Industrious new.png&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;can&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;we&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;understand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;system&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;architecture&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;stages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;initiatives&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;now&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;should&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;we&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;is&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;revenue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;from&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;upgrades&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;vs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;signups&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;they&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;want&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;segments&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;are&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;impacted&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;members&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;facility&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;managers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;        &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;brokers&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;evidence&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="w"&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;experiments&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><category term="posts"/></entry><entry><title>Atomic Habits</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/atomic-habits.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2020-01-31T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2020-01-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2020-01-31:/blog/atomic-habits.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date Modified: 2021-02-28
Category: Reading
Tags: Reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This read took a while because I was …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Date Modified: 2021-02-28
Category: Reading
Tags: Reading&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This read took a while because I was mindmapping my notes, but what a great start to the year. Everyone knows the power of habits, but this deconstructed a lot of specific things about them for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Atomic Habit" src="../images/Atomic Habits Mindmap.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major takeaways were&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;habit stacking&lt;/strong&gt;: chaining various activities together to make them sticky habits - &lt;em&gt;I started a 10pm brush your teeth/plan your 6 top items for the next day routine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;planning a fixed time and place&lt;/strong&gt; for habits you're trying to develop - 
    &lt;em&gt;This worked really well for yoga, running, reading and painting this year.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="posts"/></entry><entry><title>Firsts: Snow</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/firsts-snow.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2013-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2013-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2013-01-19:/blog/firsts-snow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably read about snow for the first time when I …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I saw snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I probably read about snow for the first time when I was three or four. Since then I have seen pictures and videos of it, imagined it, and wondered how I would feel when I saw it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All my siblings had seen snow, even the last one; who was ten years younger. It was just a coincidence I guess, that I had never been where it snowed, when it did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw snow yesterday, and it was dirty, slippery, and generally very disgusting.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="posts"/><category term="notes"/></entry></feed>