<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chu's Digital Log - product</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://chunnodu.com/feeds/product.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://chunnodu.com/</id><updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>A Social Gameshow</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/a-social-gameshow.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-28T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2024-07-28:/blog/a-social-gameshow.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Victor sent me a random WhatsApp message one Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="socialgameshow" src="../images/socialgameshow.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He referenced a social media gameshow …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Victor sent me a random WhatsApp message one Sunday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="socialgameshow" src="../images/socialgameshow.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He referenced a social media gameshow called HQ &lt;a href="https://medium.com/swlh/the-rise-and-fall-of-hq-the-social-media-trivia-game-show-3a15d58a528e"&gt;https://medium.com/swlh/the-rise-and-fall-of-hq-the-social-media-trivia-game-show-3a15d58a528e&lt;/a&gt; which I never got around to reading - somehow, I wasn’t convinced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But a week later I got thinking, How about a trending topic social media game show, exclusively on twitter? (I’ll never call it X)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It would have some parts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First&lt;/strong&gt;, a trending topic is chosen and summarized, with a list of the top 2/3 view points. This post also has a poll, so users can pick a side.
The winning side is announced after the poll runs its course. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next&lt;/strong&gt;, players can now respond in-thread with their best defense of the winning position. Other users can vote by liking a post. The top 3 liked posts in-thread, within the alotted game time can now be announced as winners, and added to a final poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In this last poll&lt;/strong&gt;, users can vote like before, but the 3 winners liked posters will have to select their top explanation from the other 2 posts.
The winner would have the highest votes from the majority and peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some reasons why it could work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most news and issues break on twitter and then filter down to other social media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a court of public opinion, and for any major issue, at least two sides of the debate always exist, with passionate supporters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going back to newspaper stands, there’s an existing culture of public dialogue and debate of news and trending topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s relatively low-effort to test out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I would go about it would be: 
- build a list of topics
- partner with an influencer to soft-launch the game with their posts(&lt;a href="https://x.com/DanielRegha"&gt;@danielregha&lt;/a&gt; is my pick)
- figure out a revenue model
- iterate on branding
- look for sponsors&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="product"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>July 2024 Take 1</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/july-2024-take-1.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2024-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2024-07-08:/blog/july-2024-take-1.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Product Weekly: July 2024 Take 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a block party recently …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;h1&gt;Product Weekly: July 2024 Take 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product Review&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to a block party recently and noticed that the wristbands were rather unique: made of cloth, with a plastic fastener that made it reusable.
It was pretty sturdy and hard to take off - if you didn’t pay attention to how the fastening mechanism worked, it sure wouldn’t come off accidentally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like it because it was of better quality than usual, and there’s a chance to have memorable art or other imagery printed, since it was more durable. It was also a reminder that everything, even party wristbands could be improved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Product Idea&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I started thinking about having a digital key fob to my building on my phone. Since I have 3 physical fobs for my building, it wouldn’t hurt if one of these were on my phone instead, would it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While it doesn’t solve a sharp problem, it does make it more convenient to go in and out without having to carry keys.  To move forward with this I would need to investigate two technologies I think would be central to making this work: RFID and NFC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for key features, this would be a one-trick pony and just allow you to open up all controlled doors you are permitted to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential impact would be that a subset of all the apartments buildings and condos would have residents who could be interested, and there might be a market in there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Product X&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Industry Insights and Trends&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re a knowledge worker and you’re not using AI in anyway as part of your workflow, you might not have given enough thought about how it could be useful. My friend Kyra kept hounding me until I made conscious efforts to, and it does make work easier in some ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A workflow to try today:&lt;/strong&gt; When building a list or template and you have some initial ideas, ask for it to complete it with similar ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example, I knew what the first two sections of this Product Weekly post would look like and also knew that I wanted 3 sections but was stuck on what that third would be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here was my prompt: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;want&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;periodic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;blog&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;related&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;product&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;management&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;In&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;first&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;I&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;want&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;about&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;product&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;or&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;user&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;experience&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;enjoyed&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;in&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;second&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;i&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;want&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;to&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;write&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;about&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;product&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;idea&lt;/span&gt;,&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;what&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;should&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;a&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;third&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;section&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;be&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="w"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;about&lt;/span&gt;?
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChatGPT recommended Industry Insights and Trends, while Gemini gave a few interesting directions: Lessons Learned, Industry Trends, Debate or a Challenge, Book Review or Resource. I decided to rotate between them depending on what was top of mind, so called the section product X.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro-Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Always use multiple LLM services if you can, the responses can be very different.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="product"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>great thinking, great product</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/great-thinking-great-product.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-11-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2023-11-22:/blog/great-thinking-great-product.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;tl;dr this could really be a post about &lt;a href="https://www.moleskine.com/en-us/shop/bags/backpacks/metro-backpack/rolltop-backpack-black-8056420854206.html"&gt;my nice new backpack&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;tl;dr this could really be a post about &lt;a href="https://www.moleskine.com/en-us/shop/bags/backpacks/metro-backpack/rolltop-backpack-black-8056420854206.html"&gt;my nice new backpack&lt;/a&gt; . &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in Lagos in the 90's, I remember a television ad for Toyota that ended with a japanese voice saying "yoi shinai, yoi kangai - good thinking, good product". That slogan stuck.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Toyota cars are generally good products. Good products get the job done - the experience isn't broken at any point of your journey. However, a common thing about products I &lt;em&gt;really love&lt;/em&gt; is that they have deeper utility  - as you continue to use them, you discover subtle features along the way that really enhance the experience and make you go - "ah, great thinking". &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great products find ways to push the envelope with delight, making you smile with every new discovery. An example folks with iPhones might relate to is the prompt to share your wifi password wirelessly when your friend needs to connect. I wouldn't buy an iPhone &lt;em&gt;for that&lt;/em&gt;, but it does come in handy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are other times I've smiled recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the lever for opening the hood of my volkswagen can only be pressed when the car door is open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a pen which fastens to my journal means writing notes on the go can happen in one action, without having to find a paper &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; find a pen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a side zipper on my backpack, for when I need to open my bag and get something out without taking out all the contents. &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;even more meta, a side zipper on the inner device compartment of the same backpack, meant I could take out and put back in my laptop and tablet at airport security with very little fuss while it was in the tray.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a roll-top zip gave my backpack extra space  for stashing my coat when i needed to, but remained portable when I didn't.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This difference between a good and great product isn't always material or price point driven, I think it could just be a thoughtful designer behind the scenes, thinking through each or at least that specific step of the customer journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Great thinking, ~~good~~ great product". How true that is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been delighted by a product? What was it? &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="product"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/></entry><entry><title>Table Stakes: Should Twitter have an End of The Year Round-up?</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/table-stakes-should-twitter-have-an-end-of-the-year-round-up.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2021-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2021-01-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2021-01-13:/blog/table-stakes-should-twitter-have-an-end-of-the-year-round-up.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I saw people tweet their 2020 recaps from &lt;a href="https://2020.byspotify.com/"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://replay.music.apple.com/"&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;, I wondered …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I saw people tweet their 2020 recaps from &lt;a href="https://2020.byspotify.com/"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://replay.music.apple.com/"&gt;Apple Music&lt;/a&gt;, I wondered if Twitter's product team observed this cross-platform sharing and what implementing something similar with already existing data assets would look like. Maybe an &lt;strong&gt;End of the Year report&lt;/strong&gt;? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With consumer technology we often see once unique features quickly become &lt;em&gt;the minimum offering needed to meet customer expectations&lt;/em&gt;. Stories which started off on Snapchat are a great example of these table stakes. I think showing users their platform usage analytics will soon be ubiquituous, and "End of the Year Reviews" are a great use case as folks get more introspective as they wrap up the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a feature from one platform is shared across others it's usually a good signal - users liked it enough to share wherever they had an existing or larger network. Back in the day before Twitter had native photo sharing it was possible to share &amp;amp; view Instagram photos but that &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/business/technology/instagram-pulls-photos-from-twitter-completely/2012/12/10/8a23bb4a-42cb-11e2-8061-253bccfc7532_story.html"&gt;was taken away&lt;/a&gt;, to keep users viewing photos mainly on the platform where they were originally posted. Sound business logic, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Twitter's Analytics page isn't visible front and center to the average user, it already has reporting features like descriptive stats, so adding on some cool natural language processing e.g Sentiment Analysis, Semantic Analysis and Bag of Words could yield some interesting results. While I make time to prototype this, here's my mindmap of how it would work under the hood.&lt;img alt="screenshot" src="../images/TwitterEOY1.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="screenshot" src="../images/TwitterEOY2.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hunch from daily interaction with users, is people could pay for it too.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="product"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>What Ingredients Make Successful Products</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/what-ingredients-make-successful-products.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2016-10-20T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2016-10-20T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2016-10-20:/blog/what-ingredients-make-successful-products.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steve jobs famously spoke about the tremendous amount of craftsmanship needed to make a great …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Steve jobs famously spoke about the tremendous amount of craftsmanship needed to make a great product. Over the years I've remained curious about what ingredients create successful products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's what I think from practice and observation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thorough understanding of strategy, business models and a feel for how to create &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; capture value&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strong research and analysis skills to dive deep into problem areas and unlock new knowledge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market/business intelligence skills to spot patterns and extract useful insights from data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intellectual curiosity: knowing how to keep an open mind in the constant search for better ways to solve a problem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A designers mind set, with the demonstrated ability to synthesize these attributes and create new solutions to problems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My approach over the last decade has been to deliberately seek traditional and non-traditional means to hone these skills. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="product"/><category term="notes"/></entry></feed>