<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Chu's Digital Log - vanitycard</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://chunnodu.com/feeds/vanitycard.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://chunnodu.com/</id><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Robbers Don't Wake Up Early in Offa</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/robbers-dont-wake-up-early-in-offa.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2025-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2025-02-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2025-02-10:/blog/robbers-dont-wake-up-early-in-offa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw a post recently on twitter about how banks only opened from 9am - 12pm …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I saw a post recently on twitter about how banks only opened from 9am - 12pm in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Offa,_Nigeria"&gt;Offa&lt;/a&gt;. Something about it triggered a faint memory, so I looked in the comments to see if there were any explanations. 
True enough to that memory, these short banking hours seemed to be due to a &lt;a href="https://www.premiumtimesng.com/news/headlines/264246-offa-robbery-police-confirm-17-killed-7-suspects-arrested.html"&gt;famous daylight robbery&lt;/a&gt; of 4 banks, starting around 4pm . I bet the bankers had a round table meeting after the tragedy and said, “you know robbers are lazier than us. They can’t wake up early to hustle but wait for us to make the money, then they come to steal it. From now on, let’s close early so by the time they wake up, we’ll be gone. Our historical analysis shows that robbers don’t wake up early in Offa.”&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vanitycard"/><category term="notes"/></entry><entry><title>Vanity Card</title><link href="https://chunnodu.com/blog/vanity-card.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2023-11-24T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2023-11-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>Chu Nnodu</name></author><id>tag:chunnodu.com,2023-11-24:/blog/vanity-card.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do thoughts need to be profound to be expressed? What if the real gems are …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do thoughts need to be profound to be expressed? What if the real gems are just waiting their turn beneath the surface of all the other things our mind wants to get out?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3 days into my 30 day commitment to build a habit by writing daily, there's a clear quality gap between when I'm inspired to share something, and when i'm writing to make up the numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cycling through ideas for today I got stuck on finding something remarkable, forgetting that the whole point was to get comfortable writing again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://chucklorre.com/"&gt;Chuck Lorre's vanity cards&lt;/a&gt; - random blurbs that flash at the end of his sitcoms - are a good example of expression without it having to mean anything. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of trying to write something "good", this is today's vanity card - a friendly reminder to show up and get a rep of writing in regardless, while waiting for that elusive inspiration. Maybe also not to spend the time planned for writing fixing the layout of my blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update: I've decided to call my own vanity cards "chunitycards", as a creative license to keep expressing random thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="vanitycard"/><category term="#Ship30for30"/><category term="chunitycard"/></entry></feed>